Tom Paulin papers, 1972-2008
Emory University
- Works by Tom Paulin, 1971-1994, Series 2; Boxes 9-22
  - Criticism, Subseries 2.4; Boxes 23-39
    - "The Politics of English Verse" [incomplete; published in Poetry Review 76 (1/2) June 1986 [See also Subseries 2.6, Works edited: " The Faber Book of Political Verse, Introduction"] (Box 31, Folder 7)
    - "Protestant Guilt" [rev. of Ted Hughes' Shakespeare and the Goddess of Complete Being] (Box 31, Folder 8)
    - Review of A Colder Eye: The Modern Irish Writers by Hugh Kenner (Box 31, Folder 9)
    - Review of The Crack: A Belfast Year by Sally Belfrage (Box 31, Folder 10)
    - Review of Literacy and the Survival of Language by Richard A. Lanham (Box 31, Folder 11)
    - Review of Sleaze: The Corruption of Parliament by David Leigh and Ed Vuilliamy [and associated notes for lecture on freedom of speech at 1997 Brighton Festival] (Box 31, Folder 12)
    - Review of A Wave by John Ashbery (Box 31, Folder 13)
    - Selected Writings of William Hazlitt [ed. Duncan Wu], Introduction, MS drafts (Box 32, Folder 1)
    - Selected Writings of William Hazlitt [ed. Duncan Wu], Introduction, TS drafts (Box 32, Folder 2)
    - Selected Writings of William Hazlitt [ed. Duncan Wu], Introduction, galley proofs (Box 32, Folder 3)
    - Selected Writings of William Hazlitt [ed. Duncan Wu], miscellaneous materials (Box 32, Folder 4)
    - Selected Writings of William Hazlitt [ed. Duncan Wu], correspondence (Box 32, Folder 5)
    - "Self-regard, Pomp and Circumstance" [Virginia Woolf; see also Subseries 2.5: J'Accuse Virginia Woolf] (Box 32, Folder 6)
    - "Self-regard, Pomp and Circumstance," notes and associated correspondence (Box 32, Folder 7)
    - "Serbonian Bog and Wild Gas: A Note and a Pamphlet," TS and associated correspondence and materials (Box 32, Folder 8)
    - "She Did Not Change: Philip Larkin" [See also Subseries 2.5, Scripts: “Philip Larkin script” and Series 9, Subject files: “Larkin letters”] (Box 32, Folder 9)
    - "Slogging it Out" [rev. of various literary theory texts] (Box 32, Folder 10)
    - "Sonnets," TS fragment (Box 32, Folder 11)
    - "Source" [See also Subseries 2.2, Uncollected poems: "Civil Comfort"] (Box 32, Folder 12)
    - " Spirit of the Age by William Hazlitt" [entry for The Good Book Guide] (Box 32, Folder 13)
    - "The Three Hebrew Children: The Loyalist Response to the Anglo-Irish Agreement" [re: Ian Paisley] (Box 32, Folder 14)
    - "A Visionary Nationalist: Geoffrey Hill" [The Case for Geoffrey Hill] [includes notes, drafts and subsequent correspondence] (Box 32, Folder 15)
    - Ireland and the English Crisis, Introduction and Preface drafts (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Ireland and the English Crisis, individual essays (Box 33, Folder 2)
    - Ireland and the English Crisis, complete typescript, annotated (Box 33, Folder 3)
    - Ireland and the English Crisis, photocopy (Box 33, Folder 4)
    - Ireland and the English Crisis, miscellaneous notes and contents drafts (Box 33, Folder 5)
    - Ireland and the English Crisis, research materials (Box 34, Folder 1)
    - Ireland and the English Crisis, associated correspondence (Box 34, Folder 2)
    - Ireland and the English Crisis, reviews (Box 34, Folder 3)
    - Minotaur, Introduction, drafts (Box 34, Folder 4)
    - Minotaur, Introduction, notes (Box 34, Folder 5)
    - Minotaur, individual essays (1) (Box 34, Folder 6)
    - Minotaur, individual essays (2) (Box 35, Folder 1)
    - Minotaur, individual essays (3) (Box 35, Folder 2)
    - Minotaur, photocopy, annotated (Box 35, Folder 3)
    - Minotaur, contents and acknowledgements (Box 35, Folder 4)
    - Minotaur, associated correspondence (Box 35, Folder 5)
    - Minotaur, reviews (Box 35, Folder 6)
    - The Plain Speaker, Introduction, drafts (Box 36, Folder 1)
    - The Plain Speaker, Introduction, galley proofs (Box 36, Folder 2)
    - The Plain Speaker, Introduction, associated correspondence (Box 36, Folder 3)
    - Writing to the Moment, essays (1) (Box 37, Folder 1)
    - Writing to the Moment, essays (2) (Box 37, Folder 2)
    - Writing to the Moment, essays (3) (Box 37, Folder 3)
    - Writing to the Moment, draft set of photocopies (Box 37, Folder 4)
    - Writing to the Moment, annotated complete photocopy (Box 37, Folder 5)
    - Writing to the Moment, reviews (Box 37, Folder 6)
    - Writing to the Moment, contents drafts and miscellaneous (Box 37, Folder 7)
    - Untitled fragment on Oscar Wilde [originally filed with Saint Oscar by Terry Eagleton] [See also Series 3: Field Day Theatre productions and related printed material, Saint Oscar, galley proofs, printed version, correspondence] (Box 37, Folder 8)
    - Lectures
    - "Brecht, Galileo I" (Box 38, Folder 1)
    - "Brecht, Galileo II" (Box 38, Folder 2)
    - "Burke and Hazlitt" [Goldsmiths College and College Historical Society, Dublin] (Box 38, Folder 3)
    - "Chinua Achebe" (Box 38, Folder 4)
    - "Chinua Achebe" [includes associated correspondence] (Box 38, Folder 5)
    - "Elizabeth Bishop" [2 lectures?] (Box 38, Folder 6)
    - "Hanif Kureishi" (Box 38, Folder 7)
    - "Hazlitt" [Warwick University] (Box 38, Folder 8)
    - "Imagining History: Ian Paisley and the Historians" (Box 38, Folder 9)
    - "The Irish Creative Spirit" [originally filed with Napoleon's Nose; See Subseries 2.5, Scripts: “Napoleon’s Nose”] (Box 38, Folder 10)
    - "Language and Liberty: William Hazlitt" [2 lectures; University College, Dublin, 1998] (Box 38, Folder 11)
    - "Larkin in Belfast: English Writers and Ireland" [Linen Hall lecture] (Box 38, Folder 12)
    - "Nadine Gordimer" (Box 38, Folder 13)
    - "Our Slaughtered Brothers: Hazlitt's Political Essays" ["Cockney Culture" Romanticism conference, University of Bristol, 1997] (Box 38, Folder 14)
    - "Poetry and Politics, Poetry and History" (Box 38, Folder 15)
    - "R. K. Narayan I" (Box 39, Folder 1)
    - "R. K. Narayan II" (Box 39, Folder 2)
    - "Republican Prose: William Hazlitt" [T. S. Eliot Memorial Lectures 1996], lecture drafts (Box 39, Folder 3)
    - "Republican Prose: William Hazlitt" [T. S. Eliot Memorial Lectures 1996], correspondence and miscellaneous (Box 39, Folder 4)
    - "Seamus Heaney I" (Box 39, Folder 5)
    - "Seamus Heaney II" (Box 39, Folder 6)
    - "Selected Modern Authors: Introduction" (Box 39, Folder 7)
    - "1798/1998: In Search of William Hazlitt" (Box 39, Folder 8)
    - "Thomas Hardy's Poetry" [includes photocopied essay by Paulin, "Hardy and the Human Voice"] (Box 39, Folder 9)
    - "The Vernacular Imagination" (Box 39, Folder 10)
    - "W. H. Auden" (Box 39, Folder 11)
    - Unidentified notes (Box 39, Folder 12)
  - Scripts, Subseries 2.5; Boxes 40-47
    - All the Way to the Empire Room [ The Break on Ulster], MS draft (Box 40, Folder 1)
    - All the Way to the Empire Room [ The Break on Ulster], MS draft (Box 40, Folder 2)
    - All the Way to the Empire Room [ The Break on Ulster], MS draft (Box 40, Folder 3)
    - All the Way to the Empire Room [ The Break on Ulster], MS draft (Box 40, Folder 4)
    - All the Way to the Empire Room [ The Break on Ulster], TS draft (Box 40, Folder 5)
    - All the Way to the Empire Room [ The Break on Ulster], TS draft (Box 40, Folder 6)
    - All the Way to the Empire Room [ The Break on Ulster], TS draft (Box 40, Folder 7)
    - All the Way to the Empire Room [ The Break on Ulster], "revised second draft screenplay, March 1989," TS (Box 40, Folder 8)
    - All the Way to the Empire Room, TS draft (Box 40, Folder 9)
    - All the Way to the Empire Room, TS draft (Box 41, Folder 1)
    - All the Way to the Empire Room, TS draft ["draft for radio"] (Box 41, Folder 2)
    - All the Way to the Empire Room, TS for radio recording [2 copies] (Box 41, Folder 3)
    - All the Way to the Empire Room, various drafts (Box 41, Folder 4)
    - All the Way to the Empire Room, research materials (Box 41, Folder 5)
    - All the Way to the Empire Room, miscellaneous (Box 41, Folder 6)
    - All the Way to the Empire Room, correspondence (Box 41, Folder 7)
    - "The Braid Tongue," early typescripts (Box 42, Folder 1)
    - "The Braid Tongue," annotated script (Box 42, Folder 2)
    - "The Braid Tongue," full transcript (Box 42, Folder 3)
    - "The Braid Tongue," correspondence and research materials (Box 42, Folder 4)
    - "Conversation," radio program [See also Series 6: Photographs and audiovisual materials] (Box 42, Folder 5)
    - The Hillsborough Script, Introduction, MS drafts (Box 43, Folder 1)
    - The Hillsborough Script, Act One MS draft [dated 10 September 1985] (Box 43, Folder 2)
    - The Hillsborough Script, Act Two MS draft [dated 11 September 1985] (Box 43, Folder 3)
    - The Hillsborough Script, Act Three MS draft (Box 43, Folder 4)
    - The Hillsborough Script, complete MS draft [dated 27 November 1985] (Box 43, Folder 5)
    - The Hillsborough Script, "blanks from redraft" [dated 28 November 1985] (Box 43, Folder 6)
    - The Hillsborough Script, [ The Orange and the Green Bay Tree] complete MS draft (Box 43, Folder 7)
    - The Hillsborough Script, [ Till The Orange Grows / On the Green Bay Tree: A Comedy in Five Acts] MS draft (Box 43, Folder 8)
    - The Hillsborough Script, [ The Orange and the Green Bay Tree] early draft TS (Box 43, Folder 9)
    - The Hillsborough Script, TS draft (Box 43, Folder 10)
    - The Hillsborough Script, TS draft [dated 24 January 1986] (Box 43, Folder 11)
    - The Hillsborough Script, TS draft [dated 19 February 1986] (Box 43, Folder 12)
    - The Hillsborough Script, TS, annotated (Box 43, Folder 13)
    - The Hillsborough Script, TS, photocopied (Box 44, Folder 1)
    - The Hillsborough Script, TS, annotated (Box 44, Folder 2)
    - The Hillsborough Script, printer's proofs (Box 44, Folder 3)
    - The Hillsborough Script, photocopy, annotated (Box 44, Folder 4)
    - The Hillsborough Script, various draft pages (Box 44, Folder 5)
    - The Hillsborough Script, research and background material (Box 44, Folder 6)
    - The Hillsborough Script, correspondence and miscellaneous (Box 44, Folder 7)
    - "J'Accuse: Virginia Woolf," television script [See also Subseries 2.4, Criticism: Essays and reviews, “Self-regard, Pomp and Circumstance”] (Box 45, Folder 1)
    - "J'Accuse: Virginia Woolf," critical responses (Box 45, Folder 2)
    - "The Kitchen Gleaming," reader (Box 45, Folder 3)
    - "Napoleon's Nose,” television script [originally filed with “The Irish Creative Spirit”; see Subseries 2.4, Criticism: Lectures, “The Irish Creative Spirit”] (Box 45, Folder 4)
    - "Philip Larkin" [television script for Late Review] (Box 45, Folder 5)
    - The People's King [Strindberg adaptation], notebook (Box 45, Folder 6)
    - The People's King [Strindberg adaptation], complete TS (Box 45, Folder 7)
    - The People's King [Strindberg adaptation], complete TS (Box 45, Folder 8)
    - The People's King [Strindberg adaptation], complete TS (Box 45, Folder 9)
    - The People's King [Strindberg adaptation], complete TS (Box 45, Folder 10)
    - The People's King [Strindberg adaptation], complete TS (Box 45, Folder 11)
    - The People's King [Strindberg adaptation], incomplete TS with notes attached [by Thorlac Turville-Petre?] (Box 45, Folder 12)
    - The People's King [Strindberg adaptation], incomplete TS with notes attached (Box 46, Folder 1)
    - The People's King [Strindberg adaptation], various incomplete TSS (Box 46, Folder 2)
    - The People's King [Strindberg adaptation], translations [by Thorlac Turville-Petre?] (Box 46, Folder 3)
    - The People's King [Strindberg adaptation], miscellaneous (Box 46, Folder 4)
    - The People's King [Strindberg adaptation], correspondence (Box 46, Folder 5)
    - "The Red Hand of Ulster" [radio lecture] (Box 46, Folder 6)
    - Seize the Fire, notebook (Box 46, Folder 7)
    - Seize the Fire, "first typescript" (Box 46, Folder 8)
    - Seize the Fire, early TS (Box 46, Folder 9)
    - Seize the Fire, TS, annotated (Box 46, Folder 10)
    - Seize the Fire, TS (Box 46, Folder 11)
    - Seize the Fire, TS, annotated [dated 18 October 1987] (Box 46, Folder 12)
    - Seize the Fire, TS, annotated [dated 3 November 1987] (Box 47, Folder 1)
    - Seize the Fire, various MS and TS drafts (Box 47, Folder 2)
    - Seize the Fire, TS text for Open University [3 drafts] (Box 47, Folder 3)
    - Seize the Fire, Open University, BBC scripts for 9-10 December 1987 [2 copies] (Box 47, Folder 4)
    - Seize the Fire, photocopy, annotated (Box 47, Folder 5)
    - Seize the Fire, research materials (Box 47, Folder 6)
    - Seize the Fire, miscellaneous (Box 47, Folder 7)
    - Seize the Fire, correspondence (Box 47, Folder 8)
    - Seize the Fire, reviews [See also Series 6 [See also Series 6, Photographs and Audio-visual materials: Audiocassettes involving Paulin, “ Seize the Fire audiocassette" (Box 47, Folder 9)
    - "Tom Paulin's Belfast" [shot list] (Box 47, Folder 10)
    - "War Poets" [Lion Television production for Channel 4] (Box 47, Folder 11)
    - "Words" [4 short talks for BBC Radio 3] (Box 47, Folder 12)
    - "World of Strangers: Nadine Gordimer" (Box 47, Folder 13)
  - Works edited, Subseries 2.6; Boxes 48-50, OP 3
    - The Faber Book of Political Verse, Introduction, drafts (Box 48, Folder 1)
    - The Faber Book of Political Verse, miscellaneous notes and materials (Box 48, Folder 2)
    - The Faber Book of Political Verse, correspondence (Box 48, Folder 3)
    - The Faber Book of Political Verse, reviews [scrapbook] (Box OP3)
    - The Faber Book of Vernacular Verse, notebook (Box 48, Folder 4)
    - The Faber Book of Vernacular Verse, Introduction, drafts (Box 48, Folder 5)
    - The Faber Book of Vernacular Verse, TS draft [entitled "Vernaculars"; to p.95] (Box 48, Folder 6)
    - The Faber Book of Vernacular Verse, TS draft [p.98-279] (Box 49, Folder 1)
    - The Faber Book of Vernacular Verse, TS draft [p.280-] (Box 49, Folder 2)
    - The Faber Book of Vernacular Verse, corrected partial draft (Box 49, Folder 3)
    - The Faber Book of Vernacular Verse, photocopy, annotated (Box 49, Folder 4)
    - The Faber Book of Vernacular Verse, notes and miscellaneous (Box 49, Folder 5)
    - The Faber Book of Vernacular Verse, correspondence (Box 49, Folder 6)
    - The Faber Book of Vernacular Verse, reviews (Box 49, Folder 7)
    - The Fight and Other Writings by William Hazlitt, eds. Duncan Wu and Tom Paulin, Introduction by Tom Paulin, MS and TS (Box 50, Folder 1)
    - The Fight and Other Writings by William Hazlitt, eds. Duncan Wu and Tom Paulin, contents and notes, annotated (Box 50, Folder 2)
    - The Fight and Other Writings by William Hazlitt, eds. Duncan Wu and Tom Paulin, complete page proofs (Box 50, Folder 3)
    - The Fight and Other Writings by William Hazlitt, eds. Duncan Wu and Tom Paulin, correspondence (Box 50, Folder 4)
- Field Day Theatre Company files, Series 3; Boxes 51-56, OP 4-6
  The Field Day Theatre Company was created by Brian Friel and Stephen Rea in 1980; soon afterwards Seamus Heaney, Tom Paulin, Seamus Deane and David Hammond joined its board of directors. Field Day's primary purpose was to commission and stage Irish drama, producing such classics as Brian Friel's Translations (1980) and Stewart Parker's Pentecost (1987); but it has also become known for its political pamphlets and the Field Day Anthology of Irish Writing (1991). This series is comprised of much of the business correspondence of Field Day, particularly during the 1980s, as well as scripts and other associated materials which were circulated among the directors of Field Day.
  Arranged by record type.
  - Correspondence and minutes of meetings
  - Correspondence, 1982-1984 (Box 51, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1985 (Box 51, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, January-July 1986 (Box 51, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, August-December 1986 (Box 51, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, January-June 1987 (Box 51, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, July-December 1987 (Box 51, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1988-1989 (Box 51, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1990- (Box 51, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, undated (Box 51, Folder 9)
  - Agendas for and Minutes from Directors' meetings, October 1982-March 1995. (Box 52, Folder 1)
  - Field Day anthology
  - Field Day Anthology: "Northern Protestant Oratory and Writing," typescripts by Tom Paulin (Box 52, Folder 2)
  - Field Day Anthology: "Northern Protestant Oratory and Writing," galley proofs (Box OP4)
  - Field Day Anthology: "Northern Protestant Oratory and Writing," final galley proofs (Box 52, Folder 3)
  - Field Day Anthology: "Northern Protestant Oratory and Writing," correspondence (Box 52, Folder 4)
  - Field Day Anthology: "Northern Protestant Oratory and Writing," miscellaneous notes (Box 52, Folder 5)
  - Field Day pamphlets
  - Series 1: Seamus Deane, "Civilians and Barbarians," TS (Box 52, Folder 6)
  - Series 1: Seamus Heaney, "An Open Letter," 2 TSS (Box 52, Folder 7)
  - Series 1: Tom Paulin, "A New Look at the Language Question" [See Series 2.4, Criticism: Reviews and essays, “A New Look at the Language Question]
  - Series 2: Seamus Deane, "Heroic Styles: The Tradition of an Idea" (Box 52, Folder 8)
  - Series 2: Richard Kearney, "Myth and Motherland" (Box 52, Folder 9)
  - Series 2: Declan Kiberd, "Anglo-Irish Attitudes" (Box 52, Folder 10)
  - Thomas Flanagan, "Afterword" to Ireland's Field Day [collection of all Series 1 and 2 pamphlets] (Box 53, Folder 1)
  - Series 3: Terence Brown, "The Whole Protestant Community" (Box 53, Folder 2)
  - Series 3: Marianne Elliott, "Watchmen in Sion" (Box 53, Folder 3)
  - Series 3: R. L. McCartney, "Liberty and Authority" (Box 53, Folder 4)
  - Series 3: correspondence and miscellaneous notes (Box 53, Folder 5)
  - Series 4: Eanna Molloy, "Dynasties of Coercion" (Box 53, Folder 6)
  - Series 4: Michael Farrell, "The Apparatus of Repression" (Box 53, Folder 7)
  - Series 4: Patrick McGrorty, "Law and the Constitution: Present Discontents" (Box 53, Folder 8)
  - Series 4: miscellaneous materials (Box 53, Folder 9)
  - Reviews and other printed material (Box 53, Folder 10)
  - Field Day Theatre productions and related printed material
  - Boesman and Lena, reviews and printed material (Box 54, Folder 1)
  - Carthaginians by Frank McGuinness, TS photocopy (Box 54, Folder 2)
  - The Communication Cord by Brian Friel, complete TS (Box 54, Folder 3)
  - The Communication Cord, Program notes by Tom Paulin, MS and TS (Box 54, Folder 4)
  - The Communication Cord, reviews and printed material (Box 54, Folder 5)
  - "The Dead" by unidentified, TS (Box 54, Folder 6)
  - Double Cross by Thomas Kilroy, TS fragment (Box 54, Folder 7)
  - Double Cross, complete TS (Box 54, Folder 8)
  - Double Cross, part two, "The Joyce Play," draft TS (Box 54, Folder 9)
  - Double Cross, reviews and printed material (Box 54, Folder 10)
  - High Time, reviews and printed material (Box 55, Folder 1)
  - Pentecost by Stewart Parker, TS fragments (Box 55, Folder 2)
  - Pentecost, reviews and printed material (Box 55, Folder 3)
  - The Riot Act, reviews and printed material (Box 55, Folder 4)
  - Saint Oscar by Terry Eagleton [2 typescripts] (Box 55, Folder 5)
  - Saint Oscar, galley proofs, printed version, correspondence [See also Subseries 2.4, Criticism: Essays and reviews, Untitled fragment on Oscar Wilde] (Box 55, Folder 6)
  - Three Sisters, reviews and printed material (Box 55, Folder 7)
  - Uncle Vanya by Anton Chekov, version by Frank McGuinness, TS (Box 55, Folder 8)
  - Uncle Vanya, reviews and printed material (Box 55, Folder 9)
  - Field Day play programs (Box 55, Folder 10)
  - Field Day play posters [ Pentecost, The Communication Cord, Translations [2], Double Cross, The Riot Act / High Time [2], Boesman and Lena [2], Uncle Vanya [2], The Riot Act [Granary Theatre] (Box OP5)
  - Other Field Day materials
  - Descriptions of Field Day by Seamus Deane and Seamus Heaney, TSS (Box 56, Folder 1)
  - Promotional material (Box 56, Folder 2)
  - Posters and flyer for "A Field Day Evening of Poetry, Music and Song" [11 January, ca. 1985] (Box OP6)
  - Field Day printed material, especially writings about Field Day (Box 56, Folder 3)
  - Other printed material archived with Field Day materials (Box 56, Folder 4)
  - Photographs (Box 56, Folder 5)
  - Financial material (Box 56, Folder 6)
  - Press releases and information sheets (Box 56, Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous MS and TS material by Tom Paulin (Box 56, Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 56, Folder 9)
- Writings by others, Series 4; Boxes 57-58
  This section contains manuscripts and typescripts by writers apart from Tom Paulin. Highlights include a typescript by Seamus Heaney entitled The Tree Clock, dedicated to Tom Paulin, containing poems mostly eventually published in Seeing Things (1991). Other writings display the mix of history, politics and poetry in which Paulin himself is intellectually immersed.
  Arranged into two sections: Essays on Tom Paulin, and Other writings.
  - Essays on Tom Paulin
  - O'Donoghue, Bernard. "Tom Paulin: Theoretical Locations and Public Positions," TS and photocopy of printed version (Box 57, Folder 1)
  - Unidentified. "Giving though free to refuse," photocopied TS (Box 57, Folder 2)
  - Other writings
  - Adamson, Ian, "The Pretanic Background to British and Irish History," TS (Box 57, Folder 3)
  - Cairns, D.W. and C.S. Richards, "'Pissing in the Gale of History': Contemporary Protestant Culture and the 'Ancient Curse,'" TS photocopy (Box 57, Folder 4)
  - Croghan, Rosaleen, "On Seeing Tom Paulin in B & Q," TS (Box 57, Folder 5)
  - Crowley, Tony, "A History of 'The History of the English Language,'" TS (Box 57, Folder 6)
  - Eagleton, Terry, Disappearances, TS (Box 57, Folder 7)
  - Eagleton, Terry, "Homage to Francis Hutcheson," TS fragments (Box 57, Folder 8)
  - Green, Arthur, "Homage to Heslinga," TS (Box 57, Folder 9)
  - Green, Arthur, "Northern Ireland as a British/Irish Issue," TS photocopy (Box 57, Folder 10)
  - Heaney, Seamus, "Making Strange," TS (Box 57, Folder 11)
  - Heaney, Seamus, The Tree Clock, TS (Box 57, Folder 12)
  - Hufstader, Jonathan, "Prod Baroque: Tom Paulin," TS [chapter of Ph.D. dissertation entitled Coming to Consciousness: Lyric Poetry as Social Discourse in the work of Charles Simic, Seamus Heaney, Tom Paulin, Tony Harrison, and Rita Dove] (Box 57, Folder 13)
  - Humphries, Simon, "'All By Turn and Turn About': The Indeterminacy of Hopkins's 'Epithalamion,'" TS (Box 57, Folder 14)
  - McCormack, W.J, Interventions [TS contents plan] (Box 57, Folder 15)
  - McDonald, Marianne, "Colonialism and Greek Tragedy: The Irish Experience," TS (Box 57, Folder 16)
  - McDonald, Marianne, "Dionysian Excess: Ancient Greek Tragedy into Modern Irish Masques," TS (Box 57, Folder 17)
  - McKendrick, Jamie, "They Talk," TS (Box 57, Folder 18)
  - Marken, Ronald, Flights of Angels, TS (Box 57, Folder 19)
  - Matthews, Aidan, Antigone, TS (Box 57, Folder 20)
  - Mornin, Daniel, In the Border Country, TS (Box 58, Folder 1)
  - O'Donoghue, Bernard, The Amateur Anatomist, TS [with MS and TS of blurb by Tom Paulin] (Box 58, Folder 2)
  - Ramanan, Mohan, "The Indian Intellectual Today," TS, and "The Indian Intellectual and Cultural Unity," TS (Box 58, Folder 3)
  - Shovlin, Frank, "Seumas O'Sullivan and The Dublin Magazine 1923-1958. (Box 58, Folder 4)
  - Simpson, Paul, "The Interactive World of 'The Third Policeman,'" TS (Box 58, Folder 5)
  - Sommer, Piotr, "A Conversation with John Ashbery," TS [with ALS dated 8 February 1981] (Box 58, Folder 6)
  - Sommer, Piotr, Inside the Chair, TS and Keepsakes Left Behind, TS (Box 58, Folder 7)
  - Youngs, Tim, "'My Footsteps on these Pages'... ," TS, and "Writing Africa in the 1980s," TS (Box 58, Folder 8)
  - Unidentified, Incomplete Dissertation TS [on Indian poets writing in English] (Box 58, Folder 9)
  - Unidentified texts (Box 58, Folder 10)
- Printed material, Series 5; Boxes 59-60